Mauricio Antonio Erazo Sosa

Web Developer / BA

Summary

Web developer with a background as a Military Pilot. Experience in planning, decision making at critical moments and in fostering a safe and trusting environment among the team in order to have a positive impact on the projects and towards the users.

Professional Experience

07.2022 - 09.2022

Full-stack MERN movie application myFlix, CareerFoundry Program.

- Built a movie app that allows users to log in, update account data, and access information about movies from a database.
- Created REST API using Node.js and Express.
- Stored Data in MongoDB, using Mongoose to interact with the database.
- Tested API endpoints with Postman, also created a Documentation on the endpoints
- o Implemented HTTP authentication and JWT authentication.
- O Built SPA with React and Redux, which fetches API data with Axios.
- Designed UI with React-Bootstrap and SCSS.

04-2021-04.2022

Operating Logistic Assistant, Gorillas Munich

- Maintained an efficient storage, custody and conservation service for all types of merchandise.
- Avoided delivering damaged products by supervising storage and available products.
- o Decreased the percentage of product complaints delivered to customers.

12.2012 - 12.2020

Salvadoran Air Force Pilot, Second Air Brigade

- Deputy Head of the Civil Affairs Department
 - Supported the population and governmental institutions of the area by serving as an interface to the air base.
 - Maintained close communication to offer our assistance as an airbase in times of need.
 - o Fostered a secure and trusting environment among entities.
- 2016-2020 Active Pilot
 - Performed flight missions according to the needs of the country, for example, search and rescue, patrol areas of interest and maintain proficiency by performing air defense practices against possible threats.
 - Planed the flight mission according to the atmospheric circumstances and the type of mission to be performed in order to maintain the safety of the crew.
 - Gain experience in decision making according to the flight assignment, as well as perform flight missions safely.

Education

05.2022 - 11.2022

• Full-Stack Web Developer, CareerFoundry (online)

München, Germany

01.2015 - 08.2016

Specialized Pilot Training, Columbus Air Force Base

Mississippi, USA

01.2009 - 11.2013

 Bachelor's Degree in Military Administration, Higher Military Academy "Captain General Gerardo Barrios".

San Salvador, El Salvador



Personal Information

+49 (0) 15906301145

antonierazo13@gmail.com

München, Germany

Salvadoran

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mauricioerazo-1bba81b7/

Portfolio

https://wichofly.github.io/portfoliowebsite/

Github

https://github.com/wichofly

Expertise

HTML, CSS, JavaScript & TypeScript

Frontend:

React, React Native, Angular & Bootstrap

Backend:

Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Postman & Firebase

Testing:

Jest, Enzyme, Jest-Cucumber & Atatus

Tools:

Github , Visual Studio Code

Languages

Spanish

Native language

English

Study/professional language, fluent

German

R2

Interests

Aviation / Technology History / Hiking Yoga / Jogging